exports.ques = [
  {
    question: "Every quadratic polynomial can have at most",
    options: [ "three zeros", "one zero", "two zeros", "none of these" ],
    answer: "two zeros",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Arithmetic Progression"]
  },
  {
    question: "For ax2 + bx + c = 0, which of the following statement is wrong?",
    options: [ "If b^2 – 4ac is a perfect square, the roots are rational.", 
      "If b^2 = 4ac , the roots are real and equal.", 
      "If b^2 – 4ac is negative, no real roots exist.", 
      "If b^2 = 4ac , the roots are real and unequal." ],
    answer: "If b^2 = 4ac , the roots are real and unequal.",
    weightage: 10,
    tags: ["Arithmetic Progression"]
  },
  {
    question: "The roots of the equation 9x^2 – bx + 81 = 0 will be equal, if the value of b is",
    options: [ "+- 9", "+- 18", "+- 27", "+- 54" ],
    answer: "+- 54",
    weightage: 9,
    tags: ["Arithmetic Progression"]
  },
  {
    question: "Roots of quadratic equation x2 – 3x = 0 , will be",
    options: ["3", "0, -3", "0, 3", "none of these"],
    answer: "0, 3",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Arithmetic Progression"]
  },
  {
    question: "In the given figure, PA and PB are tangents from P to a circle with centre O. If ∠AOB = 130°, then find ∠APB.",
    options: ["40°", "55°", "50°", "60°"],
    answer: "50°",
    weightage: 9,
    tags: ["Circles"]
  },
  {
    question: "In the given figure, PT is a tangent to a circle whose centre is O. If PT = 12 cm and PO = 13 cm then find teh radius of the circle.",
    options: [ "5 cm", "4 cm", "6 cm", "4.5 cm" ],
    answer: "4 cm",
    weightage: 6,
    tags: ["Circles"]
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of P for which the point (–1, 3), (2, p) and (5, –1) are collinear.",
    options: [ "4", "3", "2", "1" ],
    answer: "1",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Coordinate Geometry"]
  },
  {
    question: "Find the distance of the point (–6, 8) from the origin.",
    options: [ "8", "11", "10", "9" ],
    answer: "10",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Coordinate Geometry"]
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of p for which the points (–5, 1), (1, p) and (4, –2) are collinear.",
    options: [ "-3", "–2", "0", "–1" ],
    answer: "-1",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Coordinate Geometry"]
  },
  {
    question: "Find the value of k if the points A(2, 3), B(4, k) and C(6, –3) are collinear.",
    options: [ "2", "3", "0", "1" ],
    answer: "0",
    weightage: 7,
    tags: ["Coordinate Geometry"]
  },
  {
    question: "In what ratio of line x – y – 2 = 0 divides the line segment joining (3, –1) and (8, 9)?",
    options: ["1 : 2", "2 : 1", "2 : 3", "1 : 3"],
    answer: "2 : 3",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Coordinate Geometry"]
  },
  {
    question: "The probability that it will rain tomorrow is 0.85. What is the probability that it will not rain tomorrow",
    options: ["0.25", "0.145", "3/20", "none of these"],
    answer: "3/20",
    weightage: 7,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the probability that a number selected from the numbers (1, 2, 3,..........,15) is a multiple of 4?",
    options: ["1/5", "4/5", "2/15", "1/3"],
    answer: "1/5",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "What are the total outcomes when we throw three coins?",
    options: [ "4", "5", "8", "7"],
    answer: "8",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "The probability that a prime number selected at random from the numbers (1,2,3, ..........35) is :",
    options: [ "12/35", "11/35", "13/35", "none of these"],
    answer: "11/35",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "The sum of the probability of an event and non event is :",
    options: [ "2", "1", "0", "none of these"],
    answer: "1",
    weightage: 9,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "The following probabilities are given; choose the correct answer for that which is not possible.",
    options: ["0.15", "2/7", "7/5", "none of these"],
    answer: "7/5",
    weightage: 8,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "If three coins are tossed simultaneously, than the probability of getting at least two heads, is",
    options: [ "1/4", "3/8", "1/2", "1/8"],
    answer: "1/2",
    weightage: 9,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "The probability of a leap year selected at random contain 53 Sunday is:",
    options: ["53/366", "1/7", "2/7", "53/365"],
    answer: "53/366",
    weightage: 6,
    tags: ["Probability"]
  },
  {
    question: "A toy is in the form of a cone mounted on a hemisphere of common base radius 7 cm. The total height of the toy is 31 cm. Find the total surface area of the toy.", 
    options: ["465", "912", "769", "858"],
    answer: "858",
    weightage: 9,
    tags: ["Surface Area"]
  },
]